A Guide to the Papers of Frank Talbott, Jr. 1949-1962
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Frank Talbott, Jr. 1949-1962
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12725
This collection contains ca. 6,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions apply to one folder under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.). Papers regarding the Nominating Committee (for the selection of a new president) have been transferred to RG-1/1/3.592 and bear restrictions imposed by that record group.
Acquisition Information
The Talbott papers were a gift of Frank Talbott, Jr. on 1977 June 10.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Frank Talbott, Jr., contain approximately 6,000 items (12 Hollinger boxes, 6 linear shelf feet) including correspondence, notes, and clippings that ducument the activities of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia from ca. 1949 to 1962. Mr. Talbott, a member of the Board of Visitors and rector of the university, was a member of many Board committees, including the athletic and the executive, and served on the nominating committee which selected Edgar F. Shannon as president of the university in 1959.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in alphabetical order.
Organization
The papers are organized topically.
Contents List
- Athletic committee re Atlantic Coast Conference 1953 (Box 1)
- Athletic Policy Committee 1950-1951, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Athletics Committee 1956-1958, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Athletics, Special Committee on 1953-1956, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Athletics, Special Committee on--Report 1949-1954, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Athletic Supervision and Control, Special Committee on 1951-1954, 3 folders (Box 2)
- Black, Barron: dinner 1956 (Box 2)
- Buildings and Grounds Committee 1956-1959, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Business, Graduate School of--Committee on Doctoral Programs 1961-1962 (Box 2)
- Business Administration, Graduate School of 1949-1956 (Box 2)
- Classification of Students, Special Committee--domicile and tuition 1959-1960 (Box 3)
- Combs, Morgan L.--Mary Washington College 1953-1955, 3 folders (Box 3)
- Committee re appointment of Dean of Law School 1962-1963 (Box 3)
- Committee re choosing a site for the Northern Virginia college 1956-1959, 3 folders (Box 3)
- Committee re consultation with the Governor and the Attorney General on Negro students applications 1956 (Box 3)
- Committee re investigation of status of student publications and financial support 1958 (Box 4)
- Correspondence: general 1949-1952, 6 folders (Box 4)
- Correspondence: general 1952-1953, 4 folders (Box 5)
- Executive Committee 1956-1960, 3 folders (Box 5)
- Finance Committee 1949 (Box 5)
- Finance Committee 1949-1952, 6 folders (Box 6)
- Finance Committee 1952-1956, 6 folders (Box 7)
- Finance Committee 1955-1962, 3 folders (Box 8)
- Fletcher, Richard R.--Lawn incident aftermath 1954 (Box 8)
- Football Coach Committee 1960-1962 (Box 8)
- Humphreys, William J., estate of 1950 (Box 8)
- Judge Advocate General's School dedication ceremonies 1956 (Box 8)
- Law School Association 1950-1954 (Box 8)
- Law School Association Advisory Committee 1952-1953 (Box 8)
- Law School reunion--class of 1924 1958-1959 (Box 9)
- Little Rock situation 1957-1962 (Box 9)
- McPherson, Randolph--correspondence re integration 1957-1958 (Box 9)
- Mary Washington College Committee 1954-1959, 3 folders (Box 9)
- Mary Washington College, inauguration of Grellet Collins Simpson 1956 (Box 9)
- Medical Committee 1956-1959 (Box 9)
- Medical Education Committee 1949-1952 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous 1953-1957, 5 folders (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous 1956-1960, 4 folders (Box 11)
- Richey, Homer G. 1950-1952, 2 folders (Box 12)
- Seward Forest project 1929, 1954-1957 (Box 12)
- Shannon, Edgar F.--inauguration of 1959 (Box 12)
- Special Committee re possibilities of a new medical center 1949 (Box 12)
- Speech before New York chapter by Frank Talbott 1958-1959 (Box 12)
- Student Aid Foundation 1948-1954 (Box 12)
- Study on governing of the University of Virginia 1957 (Box 12)
- Swanson, Gregory 1950 (Box 12)
- University of Virginia Club of Washington 1956 (Box 12)